We actually used the sewing machine for this, and basically we had two pieces of fabric.
We used the zigzag stitch around, and turn it right side out, and we actually have a little spot that we're going to slip-stitch but I had an epiphany as I was ironing, because you are going to want to just iron your placemat so all of your edges are nice and flat.
Go around and we're not going to actually slip-stitch, we are going to use our fusible tape to finish this placemat.
So I'm just going to measure, it's a very, very little area, very small area that I need to finish here.
So you just measure and cut, and again be sure you measure the exact length because if you go over and it ends up sticking out and the iron gets on it, it's going to get really hot and it's going to make the outside of your fabric really sticky and that's going to start to bunch up and you don't want that.
So really kind of take your time in measuring how much tape you?re going to use.
Just fold your fabric under on both sides like that, you just tuck it in, use your finger to do the corner.
Lay that down, but make sure your tape does go all the way to the corner, otherwise you're going to have a little open corner and you don't want that either.
Go ahead and lay it flat and I'm just going to get, my iron is hot but not too height though.
I'm just going to get my little cloth and just dampen it up a little bit.
And then we're going to put that on there.
Again, make sure none of the fusing is actually sticking out, because if it gets on your iron board, it's really sticky and it gets on your iron and it's impossible to get out.
Like that, put that down, see how it steams, and it's sealing it shut for us right now.
Slide it around a little bit.
There you have it, a very adorable pumpkin placemat that's going to last for years.
We made sure of that when we used the zigzag stitched the edges.
You can throw it in the washing machine and it's going to hold it beautifully.
Stick around, I'm going to show you a few tricks for embellishing before we go.